Guide to the Cedric J. Robinson and Elizabeth P. Robinson Collection on Third World News Review TAM.835
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Third World News Review Episodes, 1981-2015; 1.67 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and a cassette box; 1.79 Terabytes in 496 computer files; 3 U-matic; 15 VHS; 29 audiocassettes
  - February 8, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_274
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ilya Ahmadizadeh and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the elections in Costa Rica and Laura Chinchilla becoming president; NAFTA, the Mexican economy, and CAFTA; British defense contractor BAE Systems admitting guilt over corrupt arms deals; the incarceration of Charles McArther Emmanuel aka Chuckie Taylor, son of President Charles Taylor; the trial of President Charles Taylor in the Hague; the changing of presidency in the African Union from Muammar Gaddafi to Bingu wa Mutharika; and the blockade of Gaza and Operation Cast Lead.
  - February 22, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_275
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guest was Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include missing Nigerian president Umaru Musa Yar'Adua and a government takeover by President Goodluck Jonathan; the rise of Boko Haram; the Haiti earthquake; the history of French colonialism in Haiti and other Caribbean islands; Laurent Gbagbo's refusal to step down as president of Ivory Coast and the resulting protests; and the 2009 Guinean protests and massacre.
  - March 1, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_276
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include earthquakes in Chile and Haiti; the Chilean government under former President Michelle Bachelet and President-Elect Sebastian Pinera; the arrest of a Jundallah member by Iran and Pakistan; Richard Holbrooke's suspected relations to Russia and the Middle East; and concerns about Iran's nuclear capabilities.
  - March 8, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_277
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Women's International Community Media conference; a coup d'etat in Niger; elections in Togo; the 2009 Guinean protests and upcoming election; President Laurent Gbagbo, corruption within Ivory Coast elections, and negotiations for the creation of a new government; and the Jos riots and massacre in Nigeria.
  - March 15, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_278
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ilya Ahmadizadeh and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Israel's intention to build more housing in the Occupied Territories; Israel being on high alert after Hamas' announcement of a "Day of Rage"; crisis in Nigeria due to an unstable government and military coups; the South African president's state visit to the U.K.; and the Mexican economy.
  - March 22, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_279
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the 50th anniversary of the Sharpeville massacre; Nigerian elections and politics; oil in Africa; Jean-Marie Le Pen and 2010 French elections; the Togo elections and President Faure Gnassingbé winning re-election; anti-Iraq and Afghanistan War demonstrations across the U.S.; and the unresolved Iraqi elections.
  - March 29, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_280
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guest was Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the fifth annual Santa Barbara Human Rights film festival; the unresolved Iraqi elections and the uncertainty of Iraqi politics; the death of Fatima Meer; the resignation of Dora Akunyili; and the death of Daphne Park.
  - April 5, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_281
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Ilya Ahmadizadeh and Thomas Jacob. Discussed topics include the bombing of the U.S. Consulate in Peshawar and a suicide bombing in the Lower Dir district of Pakistan; bombings in Russia and Chechnya and their connection to terrorist activities in Pakistan; and Iran's plan to host a nuclear disarmament conference as new sanctions loom.
  - April 12, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_282
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include the Kyrgyz Revolution; the Smolensk air disaster; Israel's approval of military law allowing the deportation of Palestinians from the West Bank; the 50th anniversary of Senegal's independence, the unveiling of the controversial African Renaissance monument, and instability surrounding President Abdoulaye Wade; the upcoming Guinean elections; Algeria's move towards criminalizing French colonialism; and the murder of Eugène Terre'Blanche.
  - April 19, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_283
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Santa Barbara Human Rights Film Festival; Zimbabwe celebrating its 30th anniversary of independence; the history of Zimbabwe and President Robert Mugabe; the ongoing Gaza conflict; the Iraq War; Prime Minister Nouri al-Maliki, and the Iraqi government torturing Sunni prisoners; and political corruption in Africa.
  - April 26, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_284
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Omar al-Bashir winning Sudanese presidential re-election, while also being indicted by the International Criminal Court for war crimes; political protests in Thailand by the United Front for Democracy Against Dictatorship; the upcoming Filipino elections; Egypt's need for a new treaty with neighbors about Nile River access or risk violence and further water shortages; and the upcoming Egyptian elections.
  - May 3, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_285
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the suppression of criticism by journalists of the Ugandan government; the aftermath of the 2008 Mumbai attacks and the conviction of Ajmal Kasab; food poverty in India; the Dantewada Maoist attack; UN nuclear arms and non-proliferation meetings; and Iran's denunciation of the U.S. and Israel.
  - May 7, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_286
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the re-nationalization of the Yacimientos Petrolíferos Fiscales in Argentina; the Arab Spring and growing anti-Muslim sentiment; the suicide of Alem Dechasa-Desisa; the exploitation and abuse of migrant workers globally; the elections in Syria and the Syrian Civil War; the international committee for the protection of journalists' most dangerous locations for journalists; and the conclusion of President Charles Taylor's trial.
  - May 10, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_287
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin, Ilya Ahmadizadeh. Discussed topics include the death of former Nigerian President Umaru Musa Yar'Adua; outrage over the execution of five Kurdish activists by Iran; new documents revealing Henry Kissinger's refusal to issue non assassination warnings to countries involved with Operation Condor; the assassinations of Orlando Letelier and Ronni Moffitt; and the Uruguay River pulp mill dispute.
  - May 17, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_288
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Yoel Haile (East Africa) and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include election violence in Kenya; the Truth and Reconciliation Commission and Kofi Annan; the trial of James Ibori; the United Nations Security Council's sanction on Eritrea due to its ties to al-Shabaab; and unrest due to upcoming elections in Egypt.
  - June 7, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_289
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include a flotilla trying to break Israel's blockade of Gaza; surface oil drilling polluting the Niger Delta for 30 years; an oil spill in the Gulf and uproar in America; and France trying to improve relations with African nations.
  - June 14, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_290
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include ethnic clashes in South Kyrgyzstan between ethnic Kyrgyz and Uzbeks; the Somali Civil War and increased use of child soldiers; the Bhopal disaster; the discovery of $1 trillion of untapped mineral deposits in Afghanistan; problems surrounding Pakistan's ongoing support of the Taliban; and the Gaza flotilla raid.
  - June 21, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_291
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include Mauricio Macri being charged with kidnapping and illegal wiretapping; Argentina's 'cartoneros' ("cardboarders") community; controversy surrounding the re-opening of the Libertador General San Martín Bridge in Gualeguaychú, Argentina; the Philippine elections and Benigno Aquino III becoming president; and WikiLeaks and Julian Assange.
  - June 28, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_292
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ilya Ahmadizadeh and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the prison sentencing of Raj Bhojwani Bhojwani; high mortality rates in Zamfara State, Nigeria from lead poisoning; the reemergence of fascism and/or Neo-Nazism in Europe; President Barack Obama winning the Nobel Peace Prize; the 50th anniversary of the Democratic Republic of the Congo's independence; and elections in Guinea.
  - July 26, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_293
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include WikiLeaks, the Afghanistan war logs, intelligence gathering, conspiracies to cover up information, and the danger posed by exposing some information; WikiLeaks revealing that a Pakistani spy agency was aiding Taliban against U.S. in Afghanistan; and comparisons between WikiLeaks and the Pentagon Papers.
  - August 2, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_294
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon, Ben Daouda Toure (Guinea), and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include gay marriage becoming legal in Argentina; France limiting the freedoms of immigrants, particularly from Africa; and the Guinean elections and attempts to educate citizens about politics.
  - August 30, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_295
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include wildfires in Russia; John Birch Society and climate change; French government's decision to deport Roma migrants from France; the ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine; political instability in Somalia under the Transitional Federal Government; and fighting in Ethiopia being attributed to al-Shabaab.
  - September 13, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_296
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Daniel Alvarenga (El Salvador) and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include a village in East Congo attacked by Rwandan rebels and Mai-Mai Congolese; food riots and deadly protests in Mozambique; the Somalia airport attack by al-Shabaab; Belgian lawyers readying to charge Ehud Barak and Tzipi Livni for war crimes; the deportation of Roma migrants from France; the upcoming Guinea elections; and the history of El Salvador, the Monument to Memory and Truth, and the Salvadoran student massacre.
  - September 17, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_297
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include conflicts over the border territory of Kyrgyzstan, Uzbekistan, and Tajikistan in the city of Osh, Kyrgyzstan; the White House beginning talks with Taliban leaders; the 50th anniversary of independence of African nations from French rule and a commemorative march on Bastille Day; riots in southeast France near the Alps; and Amnesty International accusing Sudan of human rights violations.
  - September 20, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_298
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the history of Lebanon, the Lebanese Civil War, and Lebanon rebuilding after war; migrant workers and Roma communities in Europe; the kidnapping of French employees from the Vinci construction company and Areva nuclear energy firm in Niger; elections in Guinea postponed; the upcoming elections in Ivory Coast; and the transitional government of Somalia.
  - September 28, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_299
    The moderator of the episode was Katia McClain and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the Venezuelan elections; the Chilean mine disaster (Copiapó mining accident); Israel's West Bank barrier and the ongoing conflict in Gaza; and migrant labor and agriculture in Lebanon.
  - October 4, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_300
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Ilya Ahmadizadeh. Discussed topics include economic sanctions against Iran by the U.S.; nuclear issues around Iran; the history of the United Fruit Company (Chiquita) in Guatemala; the Guatemalan syphilis experiments; an attempted coup in Ecuador against President Rafael Correa; and the elections in Brazil.
  - November 1, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_301
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the ¡Alto Arizona! campaign; protests against the School of the Americas; elections in Brazil and the election of the first female president, Dilma Rousseff; the murder of Mariano Ferreyra; the careers of Néstor Kirchner and Cristina Fernández de Kirchner, and unrest in Argentina; the attempted bombing of two U.S. cargo aircraft using explosives concealed in printer cartridges shipped from Yemen; and a discussion of most corrupt and least corrupt nations.
  - November 15, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_302
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include increased sexual violence in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and the work of gynaecologist Dr. Denis Mukwege towards healing these victims; Muammar Gaddafi releasing Libyan journalists; an examination of the role of mercenaries globally; the 2010 Hajj to Mecca; the Haiti earthquake and upcoming election; Alpha Condé winning the presidency in Guinea; the rise of drug smuggling from South America to West Africa to America; and the disappearance of Jorge Julio López.
  - November 22, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_303
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the murder of Eugène Terre'Blanche; British mercenaries hired by Somali government versus Somali pirates and the trials of captured Somali pirates; the trial of Jean-Pierre Bemba at the International Criminal Court; 16 Days of Activism Against Gender-Based Violence (GBV); Israeli soldiers being convicted for using a child as a human shield; and the release of Aung San Suu Kyi from house arrest.
  - November 29, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_304
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include WikiLeaks and the exposure of global diplomatic traffic being sent to Washington, DC; the truth about the invasion of Iraq and Afghanistan; WikiLeaks exposing information about Morgan Tsvangirai and Thabo Mbeki; and violent outbreaks after Guinea's first democratic election in 50 years.
  - December 6, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_305
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include WikiLeaks revealing secret cables sent to the U.S. embassy in Argentina questioning the mental health of President Cristina Kirchner; Bolivia passing a law against racism; WikiLeaks revealing that British politicians were concerned about the election of Barack Obama due to British ill-treatment of his grandfather in Kenya; and the uncertain Ivory Coast elections.
  - December 13, 2010, TW_TAM_835_ER_306
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include the elections in Kosovo and its uncertain future; the death of Richard Holbrooke and the aftermath of the Bosnian War; the EU's condemnation of the Czech Republic for using "phallometric testing' to test gay asylum seekers; the election of Alpha Condé as the president of Guinea; and President Laurent Gbagbo challenging his loss to Alassane Ouattara in the Ivorian election.
  - January 10, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_307
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Sudanese government allowing a referendum for South Sudanese independence, the kidnapping of two Frenchmen in Niger, youth protests in Tunisia, and protests againsts Israel constructing its West Bank wall.
  - January 24, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_308
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include severe floods in Brazil; the Chilean economy; the death of Bishop Simon Ruiz in Chiapas, Mexico; and corruption in India's government and private sectors, as well as economic inequality.
  - January 31, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_309
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Amr El Abbadi (North Africa) and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the South Sudanese referendum for independence; murder of David Kato and homophobia in Uganda; and protests in Tunisia and Egypt after the death of Mohammed Bouazizi.
  - February 7, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_310
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include a warrant issued for the arrest of Tzipi Livni and Operation Cast Lead; the formation of South Sudan; the African Union; Egyptian revolutions; governmental changes in Jordan, Yemen, Pakistan, and India and public demonstrations in response to these changes; and the Indian satellite program and Scientific Research Organization.
  - February 14, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_311
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval. Discussed topics include the arrest of a suspect in Canada related to the Dos Erres Massacre in Guatemala; a 2009 coup in Honduras and the election of Porfirio Lobo Sosa; the International Day of the Flower Workers in Colombia and Colombian trade union violence; the death of Édouard Glissant; Ivory Coast election conflict between Laurent Gbagbo and Alassane Ouattara; the World Social Forum; and the Haitian elections.
  - February 28, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_312
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon, Meriem Ouederni (North Africa), and Amr El Abbadi (North Africa). Discussed topics include the Second Ivorian Civil War; the Libyan Civil War and Muammar Gaddafi; Mohamed Bouazizi and the Tunisian Revolution; and Egypt and President Hosni Mubarak.
  - March 7, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_313
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include protests in Zagreb against the prime minister's economic policies and corruption; drug trafficking in Europe; Bangladeshi and Filipino migrant workers evacuated from Libya; the suicide of Filipino Major General Angelo Reyes; investigations of officers and mismanagement of funds in Philippines; and President Laurent Gbagbo's refusal to concede and this decision leading to civil war in Ivory Coast.
  - March 21, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_314
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Specialist Jeremy Morlock, Private Andrew Holmes, and a U.S. "kill squad" in Afghanistan; dissension within the Arab League amid elections; the Libyan Civil War and Muammar Gaddafi; ongoing conflicts between Israel and Palestine; and elections in France and Haiti.
  - March 28, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_315
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the 35th anniversary of the 1976 Argentine coup d'état that overthrew Isabel Perón; the abduction of children by agents of the Argentine government during the "Dirty War"; the International Criminal Court and the prosecution of African heads of state; civil war in Ivory Coast related to the recent election; and Turkey offering to broker a ceasefire with Libya to end the civil war.
  - April 4, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_316
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval. Discussed topics include the Gaza War, Operation Cast Lead, and the Goldstone Report; President Barack Obama's visit to Latin America; and the International Criminal Court indicting six members of the Kenyan government (the Ocampo Six).
  - April 11, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_317
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon, Gary Colmenar, and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the arrest of former president of Ivory Coast, Laurent Gbagbo; the Rio de Janeiro school shooting; and the Japanese Tōhoku earthquake, tsunami, and the Fukushima Daiichi nuclear disaster.
  - April 18, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_318
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Nigerian presidential election and victory of President Goodluck Jonathan; the Mau Mau Rebellion; the film Mugabe and the White African; racism and colonialist narratives related to Africa; the Arab Spring; and the Syrian Civil War.
  - April 25, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_319
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include WikiLeaks and the Guantanamo Files; Malalai Joya's U.S. speaking tour; the French film Korkoro by Tony Gatlif and the historic portrayals of Roma communities in Europe; and the death of white African farmer Mike Campbell, who was the subject the documentary, Mugabe and the White African.
  - May 2, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_320
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the death of Osama bin Laden; the Libyan Civil War and NATO strike on Muammar Gaddafi's compound in Tripoli; the Libyan refugee crisis; France wanting to limit the number of African American soccer players on their professional teams and growing racism in France; Alassane Ouattara becoming the new president of Ivory Coast; and a meeting between the The Elders (Mary Robinson, Kofi Annan, Desmond Tutu) and Laurent Gbagbo.
  - May 9, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_321
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Lucy Edwards (Honduras) and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the trial of Lazare Kobagaya in Kansas for his involvement in the Rwandan genocide; the Honduras Accompaniment Project; coup d'états and ongoing human rights violations in Honduras; the Truth and Reconciliation Commission in Honduras; and a "Return to Palestine" international peace march planned for Nakba Day.